♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
What about the mantas?
How are we doing?
Looks like they're
gonna hatch real soon.
And judging by
the size of the nest,
We're gonna have some
big bouncing babies!
Okay. That's it for now, Aelita.
Just a little longer, Jeremie.
We've never been able
to access this much data!
Let me take over now, okay?
Aelita, listen, I don't want
to rush you, but uh…
Jeremie, they're here.
Okay. I've got things under control.
Three vehicles coming right up!
Wow!
Still just babies and check 'em out!
What do you think they are?
Male or female?
Considering their tempers,
they've got to be girls, right?
Just watch.
I'll show 'em what is it to be a guy.
Jeremie, tell me, do I
really need to hear this?
Uh, sorry, Yumi, but you
can't always choose your friends!
Anyway, the tunnel will be open soon.
Just in time!
Okay. The tunnels are open.
The mantas shouldn't follow you inside.
And there you go.
The data analysis program is running.
Great!
And what does that mean exactly?
With all the data that
we've been able to recover,
I've got a good chance of
finding the antivirus.
You mean that pretty soon we'll be able
to shut down the super calculator?
Exactly.
And if it works,
Aelita will no longer be tied
to XANA by that horrible virus.
Oh, shoot.
What are we gonna do
with our free time?
I mean, if we can't
save the world anymore…
You might study a little more.
And learn something for once.
3 AM? Wow.
We'd better head for our rooms
if we don't want to get caught.
Well, good night.
You mean what's left of it.
Jeremie, do you really think
that your calculations
will lead to something?
We can't be 100 percent
sure, but I think so.
I can't believe that
soon I'll be really real.
Well, to me, you already are.
Very real. I mean it.
And to everyone else,
you're Aelita Stones.
Odd's cousin.
You know very well that isn't true.
But a lie that everyone believes
isn't really a lie anymore.
Hey, don't worry, Aelita.
Tomorrow's gonna be a great day.
Believe me.
Good night.
Good night, Jeremie.
This time, I've got 'em.
It's Tuesday already!
No, you're not dreaming!
Or, rather, you're
not dreaming anymore!
It's already 7 o'clock in
the morning on Sky Radio.
Look out your window!
The sun is shining,
the birds are singing,
and me, I'm talking,
talking, talking!
To keep you from
falling back to sleep!
You bunch of lazy bones!
It's a great day that's
gonna start off great
Thanks to Sky Radio
with the Subsonics' latest hit!
Here it comes--
Hmph. I can't help but wonder
what a girl your age
could possibly be doing out
at such a late hour.
There's a boy behind this, isn't there!
I couldn't exactly tell them that
there were three friends involved
and all of them boys, could I?
That would've really freaked them out.
Why don't you just make up a story?
I do it all the time with my parents.
I'm sick of lying.
I-I'd love to be able to
tell them everything.
Like I used to.
Don't worry, Yumi!
Soon, you won't have to lie any more.
Come on! Cheer up!
It's gonna be a great day!
They said so on the radio!
Don't you think Jeremie
looks happy this morning?
Not for long.
Hey!
Whoa!
Jeremie, would you listen
to something for me?
You'll see.
There's not a lot of music,
But the words are really interesting.
She taped the whole conversation.
But what does she want exactly?
She wants to be a part of our group.
And that we explain everything
to her from A to Z.
If not, she'll tell her father everything.
She's even worse than I thought.
Excuse me, you three,
but do you mind if I teach a class here?
Not at all, mam.
After all, it is your job.
Yes, and my job is also to
ask questions, isn't it, Odd?
So, would you be
kind enough to tell me
the mass and moles
of two oxygen atoms?
Um…um…
32 grams per mole.
And the principle of photosynthesis?
Uh…you mean…
The synthesis of oxygen for plants
possessing chlorophyll placed in light.
Alright, here's an easy one now.
Which student in this graduating class
is the biggest failure in science
who nevertheless takes the liberty
of not listening to my lessons?
Um…me, Misses Hertz?
Bravo. Well done, Odd.
You see what you can do
when you apply yourself?
(LAUGHTER)
Whatever happens, we can't
let Sissi tell her father.
Don't worry, Jeremie.
I've got an idea.
I'm so happy that
you finally decided
to give me a lesson
in Pen-sharve Key-lot.
Pencak Silat.
Whatever. Well, I wonder
what could've made you
change your mind all of a sudden!
Is it this one?
Uh-huh.
Huh?
Maybe this is what you're looking for.
This is a basic lanka.
You ought to be able to manage it.
(CHUCKLES)
Huh?
You were right, Sissi. As usual.
They were after the minidisc!
Oh, wow! Gentlemen,
did you think you were
smarter than me?
You don't know me very well.
So, now it's time to spill the beans.
Tell me everything you've been up to
for long as I can remember!
What's the big conspiracy!
Oh, you won't tell me a thing? Is that it?
Okay, then. You asked for it.
I'm gonna play this recording
for my father. Hmph.
It's Tuesday already!
No, you're not dreaming!
Or, rather, you're
not dreaming anymore!
It's already 7 o'clock in
the morning on Sky Radio.
Look out your window!
The sun is shining,
the birds are singing…
…Thanks to Sky Radio
with the Subsonics' latest hit!
Here it--
Hi, dad.
Yumi, I have to talk to you.
Papa, I know what
you're gonna tell me.
You're totally right.
Okay! I'm sorry!
Yumi!
But I didn't program
going back in time.
Then how do you explain the fact
that Tuesday is starting again?
It's weird.
Let's go to over to the factory
after science class to check it out.
At least we've got a second chance
to get Sissi off our backs.
Sissi? Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
What? You are?
B-But you see, I…
I wanted to talk to Jeremie.
Aw, that can wait.
There's something I've been wanting
to ask you for a long time.
But I just can't
bring myself to do it.
You…uh…y-you can't…
Would you like to learn
Penchak Silat with me?
Well, uh, yes!
So, would you be
kind enough to tell me
the mass and moles
of two oxygen atoms?
32 grams per mole, mam.
Uh, oh. Yes, that's right.
Uh, very well, Odd. Now, please,
would you explain to me the
principle of photosynthesis?
Of course, mam.
That would be the synthesis of oxygen
from plants possessing
chlorophyll placed in light.
Odd, is it really you?
You haven't been replaced by a clone?
No, mam, why?
Is something wrong?
No…uh, no.
Let's go on with our lesson.
Wow. Hey, being a
good student is so cool!
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Very good. You learn really fast.
You think so? That's great!
Uh, Sissi, could…could I
talk to you as a friend?
Sorry? As a what?
As a friend.
You see…I'm worried
about Jeremie and Aelita.
I know you're gonna laugh, but…
Laugh? But why?
Well, um…
You see, they've kind of lost it.
For some strange reason,
they think they're virtual people.
What's that?
Do you think we're going
to live the same day
over and over again?
First, I have to isolate the
program that jumps back in time
to see what's going on.
Maybe it's XANA's doing.
We'll know in a minute.
Odd, you mind telling us
what you're doing over there?
I'm studying.
That's what you wanted
me to do, wasn't it?
Look at that!
XANA's managed to take control
over going back in time!
But how?
In my opinion, by using the data
we recovered from sector five.
Booby-trapped data!
But why would he do that?
He must have a good reason.
I don't know.
In any event,
it's starting up again.
We're gonna go directly
back in time in a few minutes.
I'm launching a scan to see
if a tower has been activated.
I can't believe that
soon I'll be really real.
It's even worse than I thought.
They've gone right off the deep end.
But…that's crazy.
It's much worse.
They're totally out of it.
Tower activated!
XANA's launched an attack!
But what kind?
I don't know yet, but
we can expect the worst.
He didn't take control of
jumping back in time for the fun of it.
Get ready! It's starting again!
It's Tues--
…with the Subsonics' latest hit--
Hi, dad!
Yumi!
What's fascinating is that
plants use the sun's energy
to change water and
carbon dioxide into glucose,
and in exchange, give off oxygen!
Odd, if you keep this up,
you'll be teaching
the class instead of me.
Oh, I certainly don't know
as much as you, Misses Hertz.
I'm beginning to wonder.
Just think. Now I'll have to
start all over again with Sissi.
Don't even bother, Ulrich.
I need you too much on Lyoko
to help the others deactivate the tower.
But what about Sissi?
We'll find another way.
Fair enough.
I really don't think I could be
as clever as yesterday.
Not like Odd.
Transfer Yumi.
Transfer Aelita.
Scanner Yumi.
Scanner Aelita.
Virtualization.
Welcome to Lyoko, ladies.
The activated tower is on
the second plateau to the north.
Sorry, but you're gonna
have to go without vehicles
because I don't have enough
machine resources to bring them up.
No sweat. It'll be
just like the good old days.
Come on. Let's go.
Good luck.
I'm gonna try and regain
control of jumping back in time.
It's kind of quiet.
Too quiet if you ask me.
You can never really enjoy the
present moment, can you, Ulrich?
(BUZZING)
Oh, yes I can.
Jeremie, XANA is
sending us monsters.
So I see.
Separate their flight pattern.
That ought to weaken them.
Odd, take Aelita to the tower.
Ulrich and I will take care
of the monsters.
Dive! On your right!
It should be a path
that leads to the tower!
With a platform to land on?
Well, logically, yes.
That's encouraging!
Geronimo!
(SCREAMS)
They're here. Ready?
Mmhmm.
Super sprint!
Hiyah!
You know very well
that isn't true.
Hmm…these little
machines work very well!
Daddy! That's not the point!
You heard what they said!
Yes, it's, uh, strange, indeed.
I'll call Della Robbia's parents
to get to the bottom of this.
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
Nice jump. But it just
cost you each 20 life points.
It was worth it.
We can see the tower.
Jeremie. The hornets are
attacking Aelita and Odd.
Got it. Odd, get ready for guests.
Three hornets are heading for you.
Shh. Odd, listen.
You hide. I’ll take care of it.
Odd! Time’s running out!
XANA’s starting another
jump back in time!
Ulrich!
Ulrich, go and give Odd a hand.
I’m on it!
(SCREAMS)
Laser arrow!
Super sprint!
Odd! Yours!
Ha ha ha!
If only I had more time
to find a solution!
Cheer up, Jeremie.
You’re about to get another day.
So then, madam,
you have never heard
this young girl who is
supposedly your son’s cousin?
No, I assure you.
Sorry to have disturbed you.
It’s Tuesda--
No, you're not dreaming!
Or, rather, you're
not dreaming anymore!
It's already 7 o'clock
in the mor--
(YAWNS)
Oh, no! I don’t believe it!
Aelita is still on Lyoko!
We’ve got to get back
to the factory. Pronto.
Go ahead. I’ll meet you there.
(HANG UP TONE)
Sissi, I already know
what you’re gonna say,
but I don’t have time.
Don't you move.
(GULPS)
But what are you doing?
I need you over here.
We’re waiting for Jeremie.
Without him, we can’t do anything.
Leave your message.
I’ll call you back.
Still no answer.
Okay. We'll find him.
Sissi, you’re not yourself.
XANA has possessed you.
You must not obey him!
I’ve never felt so good!
No!
(GROWLS)
(SHRIEKS)
Ah, there you are!
Help me to transport
this simpleton to a safer place.
Yumi. They saw me.
(RUMBLING)
Aelita?
Aelita!
Perfect!
They’ll never think of
looking for him here.
But, Sissi, what’s going on?
You! Be quiet!
Odd! Ulrich! Look out.
Sissi is possessed by XANA!
(GROWLS)
Can you see anything?
Absolutely nothing!
But I think we'd better
get out of here!
(SNARLS)
Hraaah!
Go on. I’ll handle her.
Are you sure?
Get going, will ya?
Good luck.
(PANTING)
How did XANA learn to
possess people?
It looks like he's
increased his powers.
Brilliant, Einstein! But how!
With…the jumps back in time!
You think so?
I sure do.
The super calculator
is a quantum computer
that uses the properties of qubytes.
Every time you add qubytes,
its power theoretically doubles.
I think the po--
Jeremie, do you mind
saying that in English?
Well, the super calculator is so powerful
that it can undoubtedly do it.
Oh, no! The Scyphozoa!
(SCREECHING)
Oh, there you are at last!
Aelita’s in trouble!
Ah!
(WHIRRING)
Virtualization!
Laser arrow!
XANA’s started another
jump back in time.
We might have to
start all over again!
I’d really rather not, Jeremie!
Aelita, are you alright?
Yeah.
We just have to make it
to that darn tower!
And we’re not there yet.
This may be the code that I need!
We won’t get a second chance.
No sweat. I’ll cover you.
It’s gotta work!
I can’t believe it! I actually did it!
I've stopped the jump back in time!
Hiyah!
(SCREECHES)
Sissi! No!
Tower deactivated.
W-What’s going on?
What am I doing here?
Oh, no! My walkman!
My minidisc!
Sissi doesn’t remember a thing.
It’s as if nothing ever happened.
Lucky for us.
Misses Hertz already gave each of us
four hours of detention
for skipping her class.
You know, if our homework
is on photosynthesis,
I just might get the only
good grade of my entire career
as a scholastic washout!
Anyway, we now know that
XANA can control people.
We also know that jumping
back in time increases his power.
We’re going to have to be very careful.
The next round is gonna
be tougher than ever.
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO